Congratulations on finishing our Deep English one week course.  In the future, we want to continue helping you with your English. Let’s review the seven tips for better speaking and listening.

    Learn To See the Big Picture
    Don’t Study English; Use English
    Welcome Mistakes – Mistakes are steps to learning
    Fake It Until You Make It – Speaking and listening confidence are skills that you need to practice.
    Use Your Imagination
    Variety and Repetition Are Crucial
    Use It or Lose It

Alright. Can you remember all of them? If you can, explain these ideas to a friend.  Teaching someone else is the best way to learn something more deeply. If you can’t remember some of these tips, go back and listen to the lessons again. These lessons contain a lot of useful information on learning but they are also made to give you extra listening practice. Listen to them as many times as you’d like. As long as it’s interesting, keep listening. The more you listen, the more you’ll learn.

Today, I want to talk a little more about the most important lesson: Don’t Study English; Use English. 

Using English is much more effective than studying English. Think about it. How do children learn English?  Have you ever seen a 2-year-old studying grammar rules? Have you ever seen a 3-year-old sit down and review vocabulary flashcards? No, of course not. If you have children or have spent time with children, you know that they don’t study English. They listen to English and they speak English. That’s all. In other words, they don’t study English, they use English.

Ok, I know what you’re thinking. That may work for children, but I’m not a child. I’m an adult. You’re absolutely right. You are an adult, but being an adult comes with it’s own learning problems.

    Adults worry about what other people think.
    Adults are afraid of making mistakes and looking foolish.
    Adults have been trained to believe that learning means studying.
    Adults want to be 100% correct even if it means less communication.
    Adults have forgotten how to use their imagination.

All of these problems, are adult problems. You need to remember what it’s like to learn as a child. 

    Use English because it’s interesting.
    Use English because it’s meaningful to you.
    Welcome mistakes. Mistakes are steps to learning.
    See the big picture. Don’t try to be perfect. Perfection is impossible.
    Fluent speaking and listening is your goal.

Learning naturally by listening a lot and speaking a lot is not only the Deep English method.  This style of natural learning is a growing field in the science of language learning. The key is to find English content that is easy to understand, but also interesting and meaningful. If it’s not interesting, meaningful and easy, it will be almost impossible to use enough English to make you fluent. You need to speak a lot and listen a lot! 

We hope that you’ve learned a lot from our one week course and will continue to be a part of our learning community.  If you do nothing, you will stay on this list and continue to receive free advice and lessons on how to achieve your English goals.

That’s all for now. Expect to hear from us again soon with more valuable advice and practice lessons.