Have you ever heard the expression, “A Dog is a man’s best friend.” Dogs and humans have lived together and had a special connection that dates back 15,000 years. Recently a dog named Capitan, has shown us why Dogs are a symbol of loyalty and friendship in many cultures.

In 2005, Capitan was adopted by a man named Guzman in Argentina. Guzman got Capitan as a gift for his son Damian. In 2006 Guzman died. Soon after, Capitan ran away from home. When Damian and Damian’s mother went to the cemetery to visit Guzman’s grave, they found Capitan. They couldn’t believe it because they had never brought Capitan to the cemetery before. They didn’t know how he had found the grave, but the dog was there barking and crying. They tried to bring the dog home many times, but each time Capitan would run away again and return to the cemetery. For 9 years, he has lived at the cemetery and is taken care of by the cemetery staff. They say that Capitan walks around in the day, but every day at 6 pm, he returns to Guzman’s grave and stays until morning.

This is similar to the story of Hachiko, a dog who was also loyal to his owner, even long after his death. In 1924, Hachiko was adopted by his owner, a man named Ueno, who was a university professor. Every day Hachiko would wait at Shibuya station, for Professor Ueno to return home from his job at the University of Tokyo. In 1925, Professor Ueno died, but Hachiko kept returning every day at 4:00 to look for his owner. The station staff took care of Hachiko, but every day he would go out to the train tracks at the same time to look for Professor Ueno coming home. This continued for 10 years until Hachiko’s death in 1935. They made a statue in front of Shibuya station and to this day, he is still a Japanese symbol of loyalty.
Hachiko's funeral

Hachiko’s funeral: Photo provided by Shibuya Folk and Literary Shirane Memorial Museum

If you want to learn more about Hachiko, they made 2 movies about him. An American version called Hachi, A Dog’s Tale and the original Japanese version called Hachiko Monogatari.

Have you ever had a close connection to an animal or thought of an animal as part of your family? These short listening lessons are completely free. All we ask is that you leave a comment and tell us what you think. So help us out and leave a comment now. Hearing your opinions helps us choose better topics in the future.